1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Records 6347
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Records
1974-2012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
1199SEIU Rochester
SEIU 1199 Upstate
1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East
SEIU Local 1199 (New York, N.Y.)
6347
33.5 cubic feet
3.2 linear ft.
Records.
7924926
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 07, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6347 PUBS: 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Publications
Service Employees International Union; Service Employees International Union. Local 1199 (New York, N.Y.); Service Employees International Union. Local 1199 (Rochester, N.Y.)
7924926
- Series I. Conventions and Major Meetings, 1975-2016
  Scope and Contents
  Inlcudes minutes and notes from conferences, retreats, seminars, and other similar events. Organized chronologically.
  - 1199 Convention: Officers' Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Conference on Alternative State and Local Public Policies, 1976-1980 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - C.O.L.A. Conference(s) 18-19 April 1980, etc., 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - "Military Spending & Labor" Conference, 1980-1982 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - SEIU/1199 Healthcare Leadership Conference, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - 1199 Convention #5, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1199 National Staff Conference April, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "Health Care in Crisis" Conference - 1199C, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 6th 1199 Convention (Speeches Only), 1983 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Duty of Fair Representation Workshop (ILR), 1983 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - National Union Convention, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1199 - Convention Materials, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - District 1199M - Michigan Health Care Associates, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Training Needs and Opportunities in Industry Conference (NYS), 1984 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Center Popular Economics Metro-Act-Conference May 7, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - New Organizer Conference (Nat. Union), 1986 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - 7th 1199 Convention, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 21-24)
  - Organizing Conference (Nat. Union), 1987 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - 1993 Legislative Conference and Legislative Action Packet 103rd Congress (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1993 Legislative Conference: Issue Briefing Materials, 1993-05-24 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1199Rochester Strategic Planning Retreat, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - 1199Rochester Strategic Planning Sessions, 1997-1998 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Media Training Seminar Notes (Sheehan), 2000 (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - Messages for Today's Unions (Survey by Hart Research), 2001 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - What You Say Matters Presentation, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - "Is Your Community A Union City?", 2001 (Box 32, Folder 37-38)
  - SEIU - Leadership Conference, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Local 715 - Leadership Convention, 2001-2002 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Health Insurance Symposium (ILR), 2002 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - 1199SEIU Vice-Presidents' Retreat, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - NLRB and the National Labor Relations Act Conference (ILR), 2004 (Box 32, Folder 47-48)
  - RGVALF Conference, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Delegate Training Conference, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1199-SEIU Staff Retreat, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Nurse Recognition Conference (1199SEIU Nurse Council), 2009 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Statewide Leader Strategy Session (Jobs with Justice), 2010 (Box 32, Folder 51)
  - Glossary for Training (Gormley, LLC), 2012 (Box 32, Folder 52)
  - 1199 SEIU, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - "Preparing for Our Future", 2013 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Primarily contains 2013 retreat files. Also includes research files and local goals.
  - Symposium on Poverty and Economic Security (Action for a Better Community), 2014 (Box 32, Folder 53)
  - Rochester Regional Summit (Social Welfare Action Alliance), 2016 (Box 32, Folder 54)
  - 1199SEIU Rochester Strategic Planning Retreat, 2016 (Box 32, Folder 55)
  - Exec. Leadership Series, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Series of lectures for leadership. Mostly blank handouts from the workshops.
  - Right to Know Law: What You Should Know About Toxic Substances, Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. at Local 1199, New York City, 1968 CD (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gerry Hudson MLAC Speech, CD, 2011-03 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Series II. Research Files, 1967-2019; 1906-2019
  Contains research files and documents written on topics such as the economy, healthcare, the labor movement, politics, and especially their effects on Rochester.
  - Marxism, 1906 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Investigation Into Communism in Unions, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Victims of Charity (Wakefield), 1959 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Rochester City Labor Code, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Workers' Compensation, 1967-1983 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Constitution of the United States of America, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Collective Bargaining, 1969-1984 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Health Packet, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Black Panther Party, 1970-1977 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Economics, 1970-1982 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - S.A. Report, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - National Caucus of Labor Committees - US Labor Party, 1971-1975 (Box 27, Folder 49)
  - Comprehensive Employment & Training Act (CETA), 1973-1978 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - National Health Insurance, 1973-1978 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Health Issues, 1974-1980 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Strikes, 1974-1982 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Pensions, 1974-1982 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Courts - Judicial Systems, 1974-1982 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Corporations, 1974-2019 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Arbitration Info, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Legal Rights Issued, 1975-1977 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Monroe County - Gov't., 1975-1979 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Republican Party, 1975-1980 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Policy Issues, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Birth Control, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - NYS Law Patient Abuse, 1976-1980 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Press/Media, 1976-1981 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Rochester Center, Latin America (ROCLA) (MJ), 1976-1987 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Health Care Finance, 1976-2005 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Women, 1977-1981 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Amnesty International, 1977-1982 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Right Wing, 1977-1982 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Health Maintenance Organizations, 1977-1982 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Labor Law - Issues, 1977-1984 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield, 1977-2004 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Health Care Unions, 1977-2014 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory Safety, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Jobs & Employment, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Teamster Rank & File - Legal Rights Handbook, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Grievance Handling, 1978-1981 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Social Security System, 1978-1982 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Nuclear Power & Energy Issues, 1978-1982 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Unions, Labor movement, 1978-1986 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - From Brass knuckles to briefcases: The Changing Art of Union - Busting in America, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Union Busters - Melnick, McKeown & Mickus (Modern Management Methods), 1979 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Collective Bargaining and Job Satisfaction for Registered Nurses: A Comparative Study by Sharon Bond, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Workers Control, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Organization For Labor Action (COLA), 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - NYS School of Industrial & Labor Relations (Cornell-ILR), 1979-1982 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Democratic Socialist Organizing CTE (DSOC), 1979-1982 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Labor Law - Standards, 1979-1985 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Military Spending, 1979-1985 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Union Busting and the Law: From Benign Neglect to malignant Growth, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Planned Parenthood, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Citizens Party, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Nursing Home Surveillance: What's Wrong? (Warner), 1980 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - NYS Legislature, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Pre-Paid Legal Services, 1980-1982 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Monroe County - Democratic Party, 1980-1982 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Church & Labor, 1980-1984 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Diagnostic Related Group (PRG) Reimbursement System, 1980-1985 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Building Profiles of Public and Private Companies, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Moral Majority, Old-Time Gospel Hour, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - New York Business Group on Health, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Labor Studies Bilbio's + Labor History Guides, 1981-1986 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - National Labor Law Center - National Lawyers Guild, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Political Survival Skills for Unions - NYSSILR -- Oct. 1, 1982, Webster, NY (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - National Lawyers Guild, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW), 1982 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Unions & Media, 1982-1985 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - NYS Labor Region Coalition, 1982-1985 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Communist Party, 1982-1985 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Rochester Area Labor, 1982-1987 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Left, 1983-2018 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Procedures for Filing Complaints in Accordance with the By Laws of NY District 1199, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Impact of Investor-Owned Health Care Chains on Labor and Community, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - The Plight of the Collective Bargaining System (NYS Committee on Labor), 1984 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Charles Chuck Erb, 1984-1985 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Tips on Corporate Campaigns, 1984-1987 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - A View of Unions, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Disability/Handicap Issues, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - U.S. Economy, 1985-2000 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Researching Nursing Homes Guided Interview (Office of Health Policy), 1986 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Lyndon Larovche, 1986-1989 (Box 27, Folder 47)
  - Contract Campaign Manual, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Let Them Call Me Rebel Excerpt (Horwitt), 1989 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Union Activist Tools, 1990-1999 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Data on Home Health Aides, 1990-2018 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Bowling Alone (Putnam), 1995 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Corporate Downsizing in Rochester.. (Brockelman), 1995 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - ILR-Rochester District, 1996-1999 (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
  - Common Sense Economics - The Rap (AFL-CIO), 1997 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - The Activist Cookbook (Boyo), 1997 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Media Relations Guides, 1997-1999 (Box 33, Folder 17-18)
  - How to Use the Internet (Basics), 1997-1999 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Building the Labor Movements: Organizing to Win!, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Paying More and Losing Ground (AFL-CIO), 1998 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - HCRA 2000 and Family Health Plus, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Governor Pataki's Proposed Budget, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - NYSUT's Positions on Key Issues, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - How Unions Can/Should Use the Internet, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Packets for Labor Unions, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - SEIU 1199 Upstate Materials, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Includes transparencies.
  - ILR - Advancing the World of Work, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Credability of Doctors/Nurses on Healthcare Issues (Kiley), 2001 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Why Roses With Our Bread? (Cohen), 2001 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - SEIU Materials, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Includes hand out and Popper Democrat & Chronicle article.
  - Lighting Labor's Fire (Geoghegan and Ehrenreich), 2002 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - SEIU Stylebooks, 2002-2010 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Communities at Work Toolbox, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Employee Free Choice Act Toolkit, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - How Unions Help All Workers (EPI), 2003 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Annual Meeting 2004 - Mobilizing for the Future (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Nationwide Attitudes Toward Unions (Zogby), 2004 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Worker Center Articles, 2004-2013 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Coalition for Economic Justice, 2007 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - The Big Squeeze (Greenhouse), 2008 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Unions and Upward Mobility for Women Workers (CEPR), 2008 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - Preserving Critical Funding to Address Health Disparities (Healthcare Ed.), 2009 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - WDI Annual Report, 2009-2010 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Demystifying Unemployment Insurance (B.S. & K.), 2010 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Manual for Attorneys Representing Labor Movement (West), 2010 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - Project Labor Agreements in New York State II, 2011 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - 1199 UHE, 2011-2012 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1199-SEIU, 2011-2013 (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
    Research and information on 2012 negotiation with University of Rochester. Includes candidate questionaires, ASK movement, and handouts.
  - Worker Co-Ops, 2012 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Reimagining Labor Movements (Fletcher), 2012 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - Nursing Home reimbursement in NYS (Gormley), 2012 (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - One-on-One General Materials, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Poverty… in the 9-County Greater Rochester Area (Commun. Found.), 2013 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Open Buffalo Project, 2013 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Offensive Bargaining: Negotiating Aggressively in Contract Campaigns by David Rosenfeld, 2013 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Poverty… in the Nine-County Rochester Area (ACT Rochester), 2013 (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - Bargaining for the Future (Corrigan et al.), 2013 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - Speak-Out Against Police Violence, 2014 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Breaking the School-to-Prison Pipeline (Metro Justice), 2014 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Raising America's Pay (EPI), 2014 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Increasing Wages is an Effective Poverty Reduction Tool (Gould), 2014 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - The Seeds of a New Labor Movement (Meyerson), 2014 (Box 33, Folder 36)
  - AFL-CIO Internal Auditing Guide, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Final Report on Low-Wage Hearings (RLC), 2015 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Unions in Jeopardy (Garcia), 2015 (Box 33, Folder 37)
  - Healthy Homes,Healthy Families (City of Roch.), 2015 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - A Future for Workers: A Contribution From Black Labor, 2015 (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - Raising NYS Min. Wage… Would Lift Wages for 3.2M Workers (EPI), 2016 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Raise the Floor: Quality Nursing Home Care… (PHI), 2016 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Crispin Hernandez NYSC Complaint, 2016 (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - Wage Disparities in Monroe County… (City of Rochester), 2017 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Wage Disparities in Rochester, 2017 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Wage Disparities in Monroe County… (City of Roch.), 2017 (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - How Today's People are Working (EPI), 2017 (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - Unions and Inequality Over the 20th Century (Farber et al.), 2017 (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - Epic Systems Corp. v Lewis (USSC), 2017 (Box 33, Folder 44)
  - Articles on Epic Systems Corp., 2017-2018 (Box 33, Folder 45)
  - Employment of People with Disabilities (City of Rochester), 2018 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Repairs to the Balanced Budget Act (BBA), 2018 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Rebuilding Power in Open-Shop America (Labor Notes), 2018 (Box 33, Folder 46)
  - Where Did it All Go Wrong? (Winant), 2018 (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - Making the Economic Case for $15 Min. Wage (Cen. Found.), 2019 (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Many Female Healthcare Workers Make Poverty-Level Wages (In Good Health), 2019 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Health Systems Look to bost Emplpoyee Retention Through Min. Wage Hikes (Mod. Health), 2019 (Box 33, Folder 48)
  - Unchecked Corporate Power (EPI), 2019 (Box 33, Folder 49)
  - Finding Workers Where They Are (Zuckerman), 2019 (Box 33, Folder 50)
  - 1199 - National Union, Undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1199 - National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employ, Undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Includes research materials about unions entering hospitals and news clippings about Leon Davis and the beginning of 1199.
  - 1199's Tips for a Safer Workplace, Undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - A Union Buster's Bag of Dirty Tricks (Gordon), Undated (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - After Pinkville, Undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - American Labor Education Center, Undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Arbitration, Undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Baltimore Medical Center Employee Survey, Undated (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Bank Investigation Manual, Undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Basic Organizing Research for Private Companies, Undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Building Profiles of Public and Private Companies - Columbus, Ohio Area, Undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Consumer Issues, Undated (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Finger Lakes Occupational Health Services (URMC), Undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Headlines About the Economy, Undated (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Health & Safety, Undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Health & Safety in the Workplace: An AFSCME Handbook, Undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Health 1199 Safety, Undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Healthcare Benefits Bargaining Manual, Undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - How to Win Strikes, Undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Impact of Legislation on Jobs, Undated (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Job injury pamphlets, Undated (Box 30, Folder 26)
    General Industry / OSHA Safety and Health Standards Digest; Injured on the Job: A Handbook for N.Y. Workers
  - Labor pamphlets, Undated (Box 30, Folder 25)
    Longshoring on the San Francisco Waterfront / Reg Theriault; Labor Law for the Rank & Filer / Staughton Lynd; Universal Declaration of Human Rights
  - Latin America, Undated (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - May Day: Tactical Manual, Undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - NACLA's Latin America and Empire Report, Undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), Undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - NLRB Organizing in the 21st Century (Murphy), Undated (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Nursing Home Research Manual, Undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - NYS Law - Labor, Undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - NYS Law - Labor - Public Sector, Undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - NYS Law - Runaway Shops, Undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Occupational Safety & Health Act & Administration (OSHA), Undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Organizing, Undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Organizing - YoUnion, Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Organizing Committee Member's Handbook and Related Tips, Undated (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Origins - NC Documentary Service, Undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Research Guides, Undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Right to Work -- Issue, Undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Rome Healthcare Associates, Undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Safety and Health Hazards on the Job, Undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Sample Labor Management Cooperation Agreement, Undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Search for Peace in Central America, Undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Social Beliefs of Christianity, Undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Statement of Political Unity - Northern California Alliance, Undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Survival Supplement, Undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - The Economy, Undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Tips for Communicating the Union Message, Undated (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Tips for Community Involvement, Undated (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Tips for Grievance Handling, Undated (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Tips for Internal Organizing, Undated (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Tips for Negotiating/Picketing, Undated (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Tips for Organizing, Undated (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Tips on Affiliation, Undated (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Tips on Meeting Procedures, Undated (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - U.S. Labor Law - Organizing, Undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - U.S. Labor Law - Reform, Undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Labor Law - Units for Bargaining, Undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - UN Relevence to Economic Justice and Worker Rights, Undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Unaccountable Excerpt (Makary), Undated (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Understanding the Benefits Cliff (RMAPI), Undated (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Union Busters, Undated (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
  - Union Governance & Landrum Griffin Act, Undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - United Glass & Ceramic Workers, Undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - US Labor Legislation, Undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Why the Internet Matters to Organized Labor, Undated (Box 20, Folder 28)
- Series III. Internal Documents, 1973-2011; 1950-2011
  Includes internal 1199SEIU documents including mailing lists, constitutions, executive council documents, communications, expense reports, and assorted speeches and articles by Popper. Organized chronologically.
  - Proceedings of the Founding Convention, 1950 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Charter of the United Nations and Statute of the International Court of Justice, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Constitution of NUHHCE, 1973-1984 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Constitution - 1199, National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees (6 - 1973, 1975, 1979, 1983, 1984, 1987); Amendments to Constitution (2 - 1975, 1977), 1973-1987 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - By-Laws of District 1199, NUHHCE, 1974-1978 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Amendments to 1199 Constitution, 1974-1984 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - By-Laws of District 1199, National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - SEIU Materials, 1976-2018 (Box 10, Folder 9-14)
  - District 1199C Training and Upgrading Fund, 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - SEIU Local #222, 1978-1980 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Rochester Delegate Lists, 1978-1989 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Employment and Training Project Two Year Project - 1199, 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Executive Council Communications, 1979-2008 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - 1199 - National Staff Meeting October, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1199 - National Staff Meeting March-April, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - SEIU Local #399 Los Angeles, CA, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Salaey and Reimbursement Memos, 1980-1989 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Constitutions and By-Laws - SEIU (Service Employees International Union) (4 constitutions - 1980, 1988, 1992, 2006), 1980-2006 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Rochester Community Contact Lists, 1980-2007 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - 1199 - National Staff Meeting December, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - SEIU Hospital Contract Survey, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Report to the Sixth Convention of National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, 1981-1986 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Report from national union.
  - 1199 National Internal Communications, 1981-1992 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Bruce Popper Misc. Communications, 1981-2017 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - 1199 National Staff Meeting October, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Summary of News and Union Business (SNUB Reports), 1982 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - NUHHCE Contract Settlements, 1982-1983 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Executive Committee Delegates, 1982-2013 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - 1199 National Staff Meeting December, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - AFL-CIO, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Regents Review Committee Report On Dimarsico, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - New National Union Headquarter, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    Includes news clippings.
  - Meeting Attendance Sheets, 1983-1988 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Constitution and By-Laws of the Rochester, New York and Vicinity Labor Council (2 constitutions - 1983, 1991) (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - AFL-CIO, 1983-2004 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - National Benefit Fund, 1983-2006 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Organizing Reports, 1983-2008 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - National Union Contact Lists, 1983-2015 (Box 34, Folder 18)